Guide to the William C. Lynch Dennis Brain Collection ARS.0138
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Compact Discs, circa 1936-2011; 155 discs 123 CD-Rs; 32 compact discs
  - Non-commerical recordings, circa 1936-2011; 117 items 113 CD-Rs; 4 compact discs
    - Brahms, 1956-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 189)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Klemperer, Otto, 1885-1973, conductor. 1956 October 29; 1956 October 31; 1957 March 28.
    - Dvorak, 1947; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 190)
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1947 February 24-26; 1947 March 1.
    - Dvorak and Beethoven, 1952-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 191)
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symphonies, no. 9, op. 95, E minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1956 February 15; 1956 February 17.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 19, B♭ major. Solomon, 1902-1988, piano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cluytens, André, conductor. 1952 November 3; 1952 November 5-6.
    - Tchaikovsky, 1954; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 192)
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Manfred. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1954 January 29; 1954 February 12.
    - Schumann and Brahms, 1947-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 193)
      Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Symphonies, no. 4, op. 120, D minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1947 April 11.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 Symphonies, no. 3, op. 90, F major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1955 August 8-9; 1955 August 12; 1955 August 16; 1955 August 18.
    - Dukas, Ravel, and Debussy, 1952-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 194)
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Apprenti sorcier. Scherzo. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1954 June 1.
      Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Daphnis et Chloé. Suite, no. 2. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1955 August 4; 1955 August 6; 1956 May 28.
      Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Pavane pour une infante défunte. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1952 October 25.
      Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Prélude à l'après-midi d'un faune. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1954 June 8-9.
      Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Nocturnes, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1955 August 3-4; 1955 August 6.
    - Rimsky-Korsakov, 1951 May-June; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 195)
      Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Shekherazada. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977, conductor. 1951 May 23; 1951 June 14-16.
    - Butterworth, Vaughan Williams, Borodin, Wagner, Jacob, and Williamson., 1946-1954; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 197)
      Butterworth, George, 1885-1916. Banks of green willow. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Miles, conductor. 1946 February 18.
      Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Loves of Joanna Godden. Incidental music. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Irving, Ernest, 1878-1953, conductor. 1947 May 13.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Kni︠a︡zʹ Igorʹ. Polovet︠s︡kiĭ marsh. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1952 June 25; 1952 September 1.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal. Charfreitagszauber. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1953 December.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Siegfrieds Rheinfahrt. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1954 April 20. Most likely does not feature Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, as his last appearance with the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra was 1954 April 7.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Trauermarsch. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1953 December.
      Jacob, Gordon, 1895-1984. Title music to Esther Waters (1948). Royal Philharmonic Orchestra. Mathieson, Muir, conductor.
      Williamson, Lambert. Dinner at Lady Datchett's from the film Woman Hater (1948). Royal Philharmonic Orchestra. Mathieson, Muir, conductor. 1947 December 23.
      Contents note
      The final two tracks on this compact disc, Jacobs and Williamson, are listed on the container but are not actually present on the disc itself. See Tape 51, Box 5 for the original recording.
    - Borodin, Waldteufel, and Schubert, 1955-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 198)
      Waldteufel, Emile, 1837-1915. Waldteufel, Emile, 1837-1915. Les patineurs. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Krips, Josef, conductor. 1956 January 5.
      Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Symphonies, D. 759, B minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1955 August 18.
    - Mozart and Haydn, 1941-1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 200)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 166, E♭ major. London Wind Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1941 September 27.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 86, D major. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 November 20-21.
    - Mozart and Haydn, circa 1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 201)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Symphonies, K. 550, G minor. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 December 22.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 49, F minor. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor.
    - Mozart, 1952 April 26; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 202)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 131, D major. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 April 26.
    - Mozart, 1957 May 13-16; 1 compact disc (Audio 2, Disc 203)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 388, C minor. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1957 May 13.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 375, E♭ major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1957 May 16
    - Handel, Arnell, and Bach (C.P.E), 1949-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 204)
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Overtures, clarinets (2), horn, HWV 424, D major. Transposed to C Major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1949 December 29.
      Arnell, Richard, 1917-2009. Serenade, woodwinds, horns (2), double bass, op. 57. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1957 May 17. All movements combined. Audio dropout 10.19 into recording.
      Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel, 1714-1788. Sonatas, woodwinds, horns (2), H. 629-634. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 June 18.
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Overtures, clarinets (2), horn, HWV 424, D major. Transposed to C Major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1949 December 28.
    - Gounod and Haydn, 1951-1953; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 205)
      Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Petite symphonie. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 November 24.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimenti, H. II, 46, B♭ major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1951 January 19.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Divertimenti, H. II, 46, B♭ major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 September 24.
    - Bach (C.P.E), Dittensdorf, Dvorak, 1953 March 23-24; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 206)
      Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel, 1714-1788. Concertos, harpsichord, piano, orchestra, H. 479, E♭ major. 'M.Arnold', harpsichord. Lionel Slater, piano. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor.
      Dittersdorf, Karl Ditters von, 1739-1799. Partitas, oboes (2), horns (2), bassoon, D major. Minuet and Trio. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 July 20.
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Serenades, oboes (2), clarinets (2), bassoons (2), contrabassoon, horns (3), cello, double bass, op. 44, D minor. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1951 December 7.
    - Haydn, 1953 September 24; 1 compact disc (Audio 2, Disc 207)
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Nocturnes, H. II, 32, C major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1953 September 24.
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Symphonies, H. I, 22, E♭ major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1951 July 4.
    - Haydn, 1951-1953; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 208)
      Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Concertos, harpsichord, orchestra, H. XVIII, 11, D major. Scherzer, Grete, piano. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1953 August 10; 1953 August 20; 1953 August 26.
    - Mozart, 1952 January 24; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 209)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Serenades, K. 375, E♭ major (1782). London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. 1952 January 24.
    - Beethoven, 1954 August-September; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 300)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 67, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 August.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio. Act 1. Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1954 September 20.
    - BBC Radio 3 - Music Matters, 2011 November 12; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 303)
      Music Matters. BBC Radio 3. 2011 November 12. Includes review of Dennis Brain: a life in music, by Lynch, William, and Gamble, Stephen.
    - Strauss (Richard), 1954 May 7; 1 compact disc (Audio 2, Disc 304)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Norddeutscher Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Schmidt-Isserstedt, Hans, 1900-1973, conductor. 1954 May 7. Later commercially released in 1996, Green Hill (GH-0015-0016).
    - Borodin and Rimsky-Korsakov, 1954-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 305)
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 1, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1955 April 6-8. Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, horn for 1955 April 7-8 sessions. Chapman,Edmund, horn for 1955 April 6 session.
      Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Ispanskoe kaprichchio. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1954 January 26.
    - Bliss and Dvorak, 1954-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 306)
      Bliss, Arthur, 1891-1975. Miracle in the Gorbals. Suite. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Bliss, Arthur, 1891-1975, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1954 January 26.
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Symfonické variace. London Philharmonic Orchestra, Sargent, Malcolm, Sir, 1895-1967, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1956 February 20; 1956 February 22.
    - Waldteufel, Strauss (Johann II), and Strauss (Josef), 1955-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 307)
      Waldteufel, Emil, 1837-1915. Waltzes. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Krips, Josef, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1956 January 5-6.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Zigeunerbaron. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 July 7.
      Strauss, Josef, 1827-1870. Delirien. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 July 6.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Künstlerleben. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 July 7.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Kaiser-Walzer. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 July 7.
    - Strauss (Johann), 1955 July 7-8; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 308)
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1955 July 7-8.
    - Suppe, 1956 January 9; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 309)
      Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895. Overtures. Selections. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Krips, Josef, conductor. 1956 January 9.
    - Rossini, 1953 January 19-20; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 310)
      Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Overtures. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1953 January 19-20.
    - Brahms, 1953 May 21-22; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 311)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1953 May 21-22.
    - Borodin, Tchaikovsky, Glazunov, and Bax, 1948-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 312)
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Quartets, strings, no. 2, D major. Notturno; arranged. Tcherepnine, Nicolas, 1873-1945, arranger. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England). 1957 March 4.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Lebedinoe ozero. Valʹs. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1957 May 14.
      Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Kont︠s︡ertnyĭ valʹs, orchestra, no. 1. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1957 May 14.
      Glazunov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1865-1936. Stenʹka Razin. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1957 May 14.
      Bax, Arnold, 1883-1953. Oliver Twist. Selections. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Mathieson, Muir, conductor. 1948 September 1.
    - Mozart and Strauss (Richard), 1956-1987; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 314)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 2, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. Kyudai Philharmonic Orchestra. Sun Palace, Fukuoka (Japan). 1987 June 11.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Sveriges radios symfoniorkester; Frykberg, Sten, 1910-1983, conductor. Stockholm (Sweden). 1956 October 7.
    - Mozart and Britten, 1943-1953; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 316)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Griller Quartet. 1944 October 25.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 495, E♭ major. Hallé Orchestra; Sargent, Malcolm, Sir, 1895-1967, conductor (1st mvt); Turner, Laurance, conductor (2nd and 3rd mvt). 1943 November 23.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1946.
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Serenade, tenor, horn, string orchestra, op. 31. Pears, Peter, Sir, tenor. New Symphony Orchestra of London; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor. 1953 November 25-27.
    - Glinka, Tchaikovsky, Paganini, Verdi, and Wagner, 1944-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 317)
      Glinka, M. I. (Mikhail Ivanovich), 1804-1857. Ruslan i Li︠u︡dmila. Uverti︠u︡ra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki; Paul, conductor. 1954.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Pikovai︠a︡ dama. Akh, istomilasʹ. Jurinac, Sena, 1921-2011, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Collingwood, Lawrance, conductor. 1950.
      Songs, Neapolitan. Infantino, Luigi, tenor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Patanè, Franco, conductor. 1946.
      Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 1, op. 6, E♭ major. Rabin, Michael, 1936-1972, violin. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Matačić, Lovro von, conductor. 1955.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Siegfrieds Rheinfahrt. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. 1944.
      Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Ritorna vincitor. Welitsch, Ljuba, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Krips, Josef, conductor. 1947.
  - Commercial recordings, circa 1939-1997; 38 items 28 compact discs; 10 CD-Rs
    Dennis Brain's involvement in these performances is assumed and therefore his name is not stated in the performance listings unless his involvement was other than that of hornist. Additionally, a number of recordings listed here feature Dennis Brain's pupil, Kaoru Chiba. Only recordings featuring Dennis Brain have been described in detail.
    - A resurrection of Dennis Brain, 1945-1949; 1 compact disc (Audio 1, Disc 166)
      Tracklisting note
      The information provided below differs in part to that found on the back page of the booklet for this item. The following is in fact based on an insert included with the item by the donor, following his research into the performances listed.
      Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Brandenburgische Konzerte. Nr. 1. Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, horn. Grinke, Frederick, 1911-1987, violin. James, Natalie, oboe. Brain, Leonard, oboe. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. 1945 June 22. Decca K.1541-43.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, women's voices, horns (2), harp, op. 17. Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, horn. Mason, Gwendolyn, harp. Nottingham Oriana Choir; Henderson, Roy, 1899-2000. 1945 December 30. Decca M 560-62.
      Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Overtures, clarinets (2), horn, HWV 424, D major. Thurston, Frederick, clarinet. De Peyer, Gervase, 1926-, clarinet. Haas, Karl, 1900-1970.Parlophone, 20581.1949 December 28.
      Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Freischütz. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. Columbia, DX 1244. 1946 March 12.
      Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Oberon. Overture. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Braithwaite, Warwick, 1896-1971. Decca, K1322. 1945 March 22.
      Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. Ouverture. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. Decca, K1166. 1945 September 6.
    - RPO Horn Passages (1946-1953): Dennis Brain, 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 196)
      Extracts from commercially released recordings by the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, conducted by Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, featuring notable horn solos and passages by Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, during his time as principal horn for the orchestra.
    - Mendelssohn, 1954 February 5; 1 CD-R; HMV/EMI Concert Classic Series, XLP 30025. (Audio 2, Disc 199)
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Sommernachtstrau. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1954 February 5.
    - Hoffnung Music Festival, 1956 November 13; 1 CD-R; Angel, 35500 (Audio 2, Disc 313)
      Hoffnung Music Festival. Royal Festival Hall (London, England). 1956 November 13.
    - Royal Air Force: Music for service occasions, 1941 December; 1 CD-R; Beulah, 1PD41. (Audio 2, Disc 315)
      Features various marches and other regular musical offerings used for RAF services. Central Band of the Royal Air Force (Great Britain). Royal Air Force Orchestra. Royal Air Force Dance Band. Royal Air Force Chorus. O'Donnell, R.P, conductor. First published by the Air Ministry, 1941 December. Beulah, 1PD41.
    - Kaoru Chiba: collection of horn performance, 1997 February-March; 1 CD-R; Epson, TYMK-012. (Audio 3, Disc 1)
      Hamabe no uta (Song by the beach)
      Aka Tombo (Red Dragonfly)
      Yoimachi gusa (Night-blooming flower)
      Defune (out-going ship)
      Yuhyake koyake (Sunset glow)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 412, D major.
      Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Romances, horn, orchestra, op. 36, F major.
      Kogan, Lev, 1927-2007. Yah, Ribon.
      Performer details
      Kaoru Chiba's Friends Orchestra. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. Honshoh, Reiko, piano. Hori, Masafumi, violin. Tezuka, Yukinori, conductor.
      Recording dates and locations
      Musashino Shimin Bunka Kaikan. Tokyo (Japan). 1997 February 3. Mitak Geijutsu Bunka Center. Tokyo (Japan). 1997 February 14. Kioi Hall. Tokyo (Japan). 1997 March 28.
    - Forever: Kaoru Chiba, circa 1969-1996; 2 CD-Rs (Audio 3, Disc 4, Disc 2)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 412, D major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. NHK Kōkyō Gakudan; Iwaki, Hiroyuki, conductor. King Record, studio No.1. 1969 December 14; 1969 December 21.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 417, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. NHK Kōkyō Gakudan; Iwaki, Hiroyuki, conductor. King Record, studio No.1. 1969 December 14; 1969 December 21.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. NHK Kōkyō Gakudan; Iwaki, Hiroyuki, conductor. King Record, studio No.1. 1969 December 14; 1969 December 21.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 495, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. NHK Kōkyō Gakudan; Iwaki, Hiroyuki, conductor. King Record, studio No.1. 1969 December 14; 1969 December 21.
      Mayuzumi, Toshirō, 1929-1997. Divertimento for 10 instruments. King Record, studio No.1. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn.
      Noda,Teruyuki. Trio for violin, horn, and piano. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. Tanaka, Chikao, violin. King Record, studio No.1.
      Toyama, Yūzō, 1931-. Passa tempo. Tokyo Horn Club. Aobadai Philia Hall. Yokohama-shi (Japan). 1996 August 13-14.
    - Art of Kaoru Chiba, The, 1984 March 20-24; 1 CD-R (Audio 3, Disc 3)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. Victor studio. 1984 March 20.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. Chiba, Kaoru, 1928-2008, horn. Shinjuku Bunka Center. 1984 March 28.
      Source of information
      Dates and recording locations have been derived from OCLC record 34372819.
    - World of Dennis Brain, The, 1944-1953; 1 compact disc; Beulah, 1PD35 (Audio 3, Disc 5)
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1944 June 8.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Per pietà, bell'idol mio. Cross, Joan, soprano. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Collingwood, Lawrance, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1947 January 2.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, horn, piano, op. 17, F major. Matthews, Denis, piano. Denham Studios. 1951.
      Williams, Edward Aneurin, 1921-. Open House. James, Natalie, oboe. Walton, Bernard (Clarinetist), clarinet. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. Riverside Studios. 1951 September.
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Moore, Gerald, 1899-1987, piano. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1952 April 19.
    - Frederick Thurston (1901-1953), 1948-1952; 1 compact disc; Symposium, 1259. (Audio 3, Disc 6)
      Fibich, Zdeněk, 1850-1900. Quintet, piano, clarinet, horn, violin, cello, op. 42, D major. Thurston, Frederick, clarinet. Wilson, Marie, 1903-, violin. Whitehead, James, 1912-1979, cello. Fuchsova, Liza, 1913-1977, piano.
    - Idomeneo, 1951 June 30; 2 compact discs; Symposium, 1274 and 1275. (Audio 3, Disc 7)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Idomeneo. Glyndebourne Festival Chorus. Glyndebourne Festival Orchestra; Busch, Fritz, 1890-1951, conductor. 1951 June 30.
    - Britten: Serenade, 1944 May - October; 1 compact disc; London, 4259962 (Audio 3, Disc 8)